A Guide to the Near East Foundation records, Accession 2010:020, RG 3 FA1306
Rockefeller Archive Center
Near East Foundation records, Accession 2010:020, RG 3
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Near East Foundation
FA1306
0.19 Cubic Feet half-letter document box
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged item may be restricted at the discretion of RAC.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Arrangement
As received.
Separated Materials
Special format items (audio, film, video, library materials, memorabilia, oversize, and photographic material) have been separated from the body of the collection and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
- Near East Foundation records, Accession 2010:020, RG 3, undated; 3; 0.25 Cubic Feet 1 1/2 letter sized document box
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Near East Foundation collection donated to Rockefeller Archive Center by Charles Benjamin, NEF President, June 2011.
  Accessioned by RAC as Accession 2010:020.
  - Nicholas Yarrow #5 (Box 1)
    - Nicholas Yarrow #5, 2010:020:004; Photographic Negative (Box 1)
  - Nicholas Yarrow #1 (Box 1)
    - Nicholas Yarrow #1, 2010:020:005; Photographic negative (Box 1)
  - Nicholas (Box 1)
    - Nicholas, 2010:020:006; Photographic negative (Box 1)
  - Nicholas 139 (Photocopy of print that matches "Nicholas" photo negative) (Box 1)
  - NEF Exhibit (Box 1)
    - NEF Exhibit, 2010:020:001; DVD (Box 1)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Access copy currently unavailable. Please see a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Near East Relief (Box 1)
    - Near East Relief, 2010:020:002; DVD (Box 1)
  - Music by Ara Gevorgian; Adana, 1915 (Box 1)
    - Music by Ara Gevorgian; Adana, 1915; 2010:020:003; CD (Box 1)
  - A People in Exhile; one year from the Armenians' history. Alma Johansson (Box 1)
  - "Experience as a Civilian Nurse with Near East Foundation and the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration During and After World War II" by Ruth Faust Morrissey (Box 1)
  - Photocopies of possible future donated material (Box 1)
  - Vansem (Box 1)
  - Oral History of Irving T. Grumb (Box 1)